so in this lesson we're going to be
looking at how to improve the IPC
without a further execution and how to
design actual Hardware that does that
for improving the IPC we have seen that
the ILP can be good it can be
significantly larger than one usually
it's way over four but to achieve
something close to that ILP we need to
handle the control dependencies and we
have seen how Branch prediction can help
eliminate control dependencies if branch
prediction is correct so if our Branch
prediction is very good which on today's
processor it is then as far as control
dependencies are concerned our IPC will
be very close to the ILP then we have to
consider the right after right and right
after read data dependencies also known
as false dependencies and we have seen
that a technique called register
renaming can completely eliminate these
dependencies so that you simply don't
have them anymore in your program at
which point they're not going to be a
problem for our IPC and then we have
seen that there are these right after
read also known as through data
dependencies and we have seen that it
helps a lot when you can execute
instructions out of order meaning you
don't strictly follow the program order
you simply find instructions whose
inputs are ready and you execute them
then that is how ILP mostly was good and
finally there are these structural
dependencies which is when you cannot
execute things simply because you don't
have enough resources in the processor
but that can be solved simply by
investing in a in to a wider issue
processor meaning we need a processor
that can handle a bunch of instructions
in each cycle and not have to delay
instructions just because it doesn't
have resources for it so among these we
really need to figure out how to do
these three and first we will focus on
this so how do we actually do register
naming and outof Order execution in a
way that can be amenable to Hardware
implementation so we know how to do it
kind of manually on paper but how does a
processor actually do it so this will
really focus on how to do this for real